Gyasi Sutton

337-258-6134 | gyasis@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Completed a 6-year Medical program in Naples, Italy, and received Laurea Magistrale in Chirurgia and Medicina (the equivalent of a U.S. M.D. or a UK MBBS) and received a Master's in Public Health. Received training in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence with applications to clinical and population medicine. Experience in multiple data acquisition strategies, data processing, and familiarity with many database technologies. Full understanding of clinical trials with GCP and knowledge of FDA guidelines.

SKILLS

Python

· R

Data visualization

· SAS

Project Facilitator

· Data Analysis

EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant

Oracle, 2022 - Current

- · Formed relationships and drove successful clinical engagements
- Lead client meetings and facilitated discussions around the adoption of technology and used industry information and data analytics to produce recommendations.
- · Provided clinical guidance and expertise to the internal project team.
- Supported engagement management team in ensuring project deliverables and timelines were met to deliver value to the client as committed.

Senior Health Data Analyst

Ripple Effect, 2021 - Current

- Cleaned and Processed data for public health agencies, pharmaceutical corporations, and government entities
- · Programming with SAS and python to extract, and visualize data (Mostly HEDIS)
- · Used Natural Language Processing for document parsing
- · Created Artificial Intelligence algorithms
- Involved with Surveillance Data acquisition and data visualization of infectious disease data of immigrants in the Lombardi Region
- · Participated in the formulation of long and short-range plans, policies, and strategies for disease control
- · Specialist in cloud-based databases,
- · Programming in python, R and SAS
- · Performing aggregation, search, and analysis of big data (EUROSTAT, HEDIS)

Medical Consultant and Programmer

Twice Data, 2019 - 2022

- · Computer Vision Gait Detection of Patient's with Neurological Diseases
- Backend Medical Server HEDIS programmer

Paramedic

New Orleans EMS, 2013 - 2014

· Care, treatment, and stabilization of critical and non-critical patients, through busy 911system

EDUCATION

Master's of Public Health: Public Heath, Epidemiology University of New England, Dec 2020

Laurea Magistrale in Medicina and Chirurgia: Magistrale Chirurgia Università degli studi della Campania Luigi Vanvitelli, Naples, Italy, Jul 2020 European 6-year program in Medicine and Surgery, Faculty of Medicine and Surgery

Bachelor of Applied Science Youngstown State University, Jan 2016

Associates of Applied Science

Mid-plains Community College, Nebraska, Jan 2012

Traditional 2-year associate program McCook, Department of Emergency Services, Paramedic Training